Finding Aid for Ward L. Quaal Papers, 1941-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ward L. Quaal Papers 1941-2004
Quaal, Ward L.
9 oversize volumes and 0.3 linear ft.
0607 Aa 2; AC
Broadcasting executive, mainly with WGN Continental Broadcasting Co. in Chicago; scrapbooks containing clippings, photographs, programs, and memorabilia from his career when he first joined WGN in 1941 until 2004.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Ward L. Quaal (donor no. 4379 ) and came to the library in December 2005.
The collection is open to research.
Born April 7, 1919 in Ishpeming, Michigan, Ward L. Quaal is a renowned broadcasting executive and innovator, serving with several broadcasting entities, but mainly with WGN Continental Broadcasting Co. (now Tribune Broadcasting Co.). He graduated from the University of Michigan in 1941, then went to worked for WGN. After three years of wartime service, 1942-1945, he returned to WGN as special assistant to the general manager. From 1949 to 1952, Quaal took a leave of absence from WGN to become executive director of the Clear Channel Broadcasting Service in Washington DC. He later served as president and chief executive officer of the Service from 1964 to 1974. In 1952, Quaal joined the Crosley Broadcasting Corp. as assistant general manager, later vice president and general manager of Crosley's radio, television and short wave properties. In 1956, he returned to WGN as vice president and general manager. Then in 1963, he was elected president of the Company. In 1975, he retired to form Ward L. Quaal Company, a broadcasting consultation and lobbying service.
The Quaal collection consists of nine scrapbooks covering the period of 1941 to 2004 and consisting of clippings, photographs, programs and other published materials, and various other memorabilia from all periods of his career in broadcasting. These scrapbooks are accompanied by a detailed index. In addition, the collection includes photocopies of letters that Quaal received from US presidents and other notable public figures. There is also a folder of biographical information.
Subjects:
Quaal, Ward L.; Broadcasting--United States.; Radio broadcasting--United States--Management.; Television broadcasting--United States--Management.; WGN (Radio station: Chicago, Ill.); WGN (Television station: Chicago, Ill.)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Scrapbooks
  (oversize volumes)
  - 1941-1961 (Volume 1)
    (volume no. 1)
  - 1961-1962 (Volume 2)
    (volume no. 2)
  - 1962-1964 (Volume 3)
    (volume no. 3)
  - 1964-1966 (Volume 4)
    (volume no. 4)
  - 1966-1968 (Volume 5)
    (volume no. 5)
  - 1968-1970 (Volume 6)
    (volume no. 6)
  - 1970-1973 (Volume 7)
    (volume no. 7)
  - 1973-1985 (Volume 8)
    (volume no. 8)
  - 1985-2004 (Volume 9)
    (volume no. 9)
- Other Papers
  - Index to the scrapbooks (Box 1)
  - Photocopies of letters from US Presidents and other public figures (Box 1)
    (mainly thank you letters and letters of appreciation)
  - Biographical miscellaneous (Box 1)